<chapter id="chapter.gui.new" xreflabel="Creating a New CDD">
  <title>Creating a New CDD</title>
  <para>
  Creating a new CDD file from the GUI can be accomplished by either clicking on the "Generate New CDD File" button in
  the Wizard window (see <xref linkend="chapter.gui.wizard"> for more details on this window), by selecting the
  <code>File -> Generate -> New CDD...</code> menu option, or using the shortcut "Shift-Control-N".  This file creation
  "wizard" allows the user to create a new CDD file that can be opened/merged into the GUI for coverage analysis.  The
  methods that the CDD creation GUI allows for creating a new CDD file are quite flexible and are completely compatible
  with the command-line commands.
  </para>
  <para>
  The following subsections describe the various windows used to create a GUI.  Note that the CDD creation wizard
  uses several "pages" to describe the various options to set for creating a new CDD file, using "Back" and "Next" 
  buttons on each page for navigation.  Clicking on the "Back" button will not cause previously filled in pages to be
  reverted to their default values but rather will remain populated with the user's data. Similarly, if a page has been
  filled in with data and the "Back" button is clicked and then the "Next" button is clicked, the page contents are
  retained.  The only way to clear out fields is to click the "Cancel" button at the bottom of each page and startup
  the CDD creation wizard again.
  </para>
  <para>
  Clicking the "Cancel" button at any time will cause the CDD creation wizard to immediately exit.  Clicking on the
  "Help" button at any time will bring up the user documentation for the current page (context sensitive help).
  </para>
  
  <sect1 id="section.gui.new.select" xreflabel="Navigating the New CDD Creation Option Selection Page">
    <title>Navigating the New CDD Creation Option Selection Window</title>
    <para>
    Figure <xref linkend="figure.gui.new.select"> shows the look of this page of the CDD creation wizard.
    </para>
    <para>
      <figure id="figure.gui.new.select" xreflabel="CDD Creation Option Selection Page">
        <title>CDD Creation Option Selection Page</title>
        <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="img/new_cdd_selection.gif" format="GIF"></imageobject></mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </para>
    <para>
    The first page of the CDD creation window allows the user to select whether all options should be interactiely
    selected within the GUI or if a file should be read in which contains command-line options to the score command
    to use.  If the latter is chosen, the contents of that file are read in and are populated in the GUI, but the
    CDD creation wizard will continue in the same fashion as the first option, allowing the user to change, remove or
    add to the options found in that file.
    </para>
    <para>
    If the <emphasis role="bold">Create CDD by interactively selecting options</emphasis> entry is currently selected 
    and the user wishes to not use a command-line file to populate the rest of the CDD creation pages, simply click on 
    the <emphasis role="bold">Next</emphasis> button at the bottom of the page to continue.  If the 
    <emphasis role="bold">Create CDD by using option file</emphasis> entry is currently selected, the user must either 
    type a valid filename or select one by clicking the <emphasis role="bold">Browse...</emphasis> button to the right 
    of the file entry area and select a valid file. Once a valid filename is selected, the 
    <emphasis role="bold">Next</emphasis> button will be enabled and the user may then click it to continue to the next 
    page. Note that any filename can be selected (whether it's a valid command file or not).  Only valid score command 
    options found in that file are used to populate the wizard entries. No error message will be displayed if the file 
    does not contain this information.
    </para>
  </sect1>
  
  <sect1 id="section.gui.new.name" xreflabel="Navigating the New CDD Creation Output Name Page">
    <title>Navigating the New CDD Creation CDD Name Page</title>
    <para>
    This page is used to specify the name of the output CDD file.  Figure <xref linkend="figure.gui.new.name"> shows 
    the display of this page.
    </para>
    <para>
      <figure id="figure.gui.new.name" xreflabel="CDD Creation Output Name Page">
        <title>CDD Creation Output Name Page</title>
        <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="img/new_cdd_name.gif" format="GIF"></imageobject></mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </para>
    <para>
    The output CDD name must be specified and, as such, the <emphasis role="bold">Next</emphasis> button is disabled
    until a name is specified in the entry field.  Any filename is allowed.  If the user wishes to make use of a
    "Save As" style window for creating a filename, click the <emphasis role="bold">Browse...</emphasis> button and use
    the window for creating a filename. When the <emphasis role="bold">Save</emphasis> button is clicked, the specified
    filename is placed in the entry field and the <emphasis role="bold">Next</emphasis> button is enabled.
    </para>
  </sect1>
  
  <sect1 id="section.gui.new.type" xreflabel="CDD Creation Type Page">
    <title>CDD Creation Type Page</title>
    <para>
    This page is used to specify what type of CDD file to create. The three types CDD files that can be created are:
    </para>
    <para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
          An unscored CDD file that was created by parsing the design. This CDD file can later be scored via a VCD or
          LXT dumpfile. 
          </para>
          <para>
          This option can be chosen by selecting the <emphasis role="bold">Parse Design Only</emphasis> radiobutton.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
          A scored CDD file created from the design and from a previously created VCD or LXT dumpfile. 
          </para>
          <para>
          This option can be chosen by selecting the <emphasis role="bold">Dumpfile:</emphasis> option. If this option 
          is chosen, a VCD or LXT dumpfile is required to be specified before the next option page can be used. Either 
          specify this dumpfile name by typing in an existing dumpfile name in the entry field or use the 
          <emphasis role="bold">Browse...</emphasis> button to select a dumpfile.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
          An unscored CDD file, a top-level Verilog file containing a PLI call to run Covered in VPI mode, and a PLI
          tab file that can be used by some simulators for compilation purposes. See <xref linkend="section.vpi"> for
          details on how to use these files for simulation/scoring purposes. 
          </para>
          <para>
          This option can be chosen by selecting the <emphasis role="bold">VPI Module:</emphasis> radiobutton. If this 
          option is chosen, the name specified will be the name of the module created that is used to allow Covered
          to run in VPI mode within a simulation.
          </para>
          <para>
          In addition to providing a module name when this option is selected, the simulator type that will be used
          when scoring can be specified as well as the timescale information that can, optionally, be specified at the
          top of the generated module.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </para>
    <para>
    Figure <xref linkend="figure.gui.new.type"> displays the contents of this page. When all necessary fields have been
    specified, the <emphasis role="bold">Next</emphasis> button will be enabled and clicking it will lead to the next
    option page.
    </para>
    <para>
      <figure id="figure.gui.new.type" xreflabel="CDD Creation Type Page">
        <title>CDD Creation Type Page</title>
        <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="img/new_cdd_type.gif" format="GIF"></imageobject></mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </para>
  </sect1>
  
  <sect1 id="section.gui.new.options1" xreflabel="CDD Creation Options1 Page">
    <title>CDD Creation Options1 Page</title>
    <para>
    This page is used to specify several options to Covered's score command. See figure 
    <xref linkend="figure.gui.new.options1"> for the layout of this window.
    </para>
    <para>
      <figure id="figure.gui.new.options1" xreflabel="CDD Creation Options1 Page">
        <title>CDD Creation Options1 Page</title>
        <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="img/new_cdd_options.gif" format="GIF"></imageobject></mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </para>
    <para>
    The following is a description about each of the CDD creation options available on this page.
    </para>
    
    <sect2 id="section.gui.new.options1.general" xreflabel="CDD Creation Option1 Page - General Options">
      <title>General Options</title>
      <para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Toplevel module name</emphasis></para>
            <para>Required? <emphasis>Yes</emphasis></para>
            <para>
            TBD
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Root pathname</emphasis></para>
            <para>Required? <emphasis>No</emphasis></para>
            <para>
            TBD
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Delay Type</emphasis></para>
            <para>
            TBD
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Race Condition Action</emphasis></para>
            <para>
            TBD
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Use embedded race condition pragmas</emphasis></para>
            <para>
            TBD
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Default Verilog Generation</emphasis></para>
            <para>
            TBD
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Include OVL Assertions</emphasis></para>
            <para>
            TBD
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </para>
    </sect2>
    
    <sect2 id="section.gui.new.options1.exclude" xreflabel="CDD Creation Options1 Page - Exclude Options">
      <title>Exclude Options</title>
      <para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Exclude Always Blocks</emphasis></para>
            <para>
            TBD
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Exclude Assign Blocks</emphasis></para>
            <para>
            TBD
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Exclude Initial Blocks</emphasis></para>
            <para>
            TBD
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Exclude Final Blocks</emphasis></para>
            <para>
            TBD
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Exclude Within Pragma</emphasis></para>
            <para>
            TBD
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </para>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>
</chapter>