<chapter id="chapter.gui.new" xreflabel="Creating a New CDD">
  <title>Creating a New CDD</title>
  <para>
  Creating a new CDD file from the GUI can be accomplished by either clicking on the "Generate New CDD File" button in
  the Wizard window (see <xref linkend="chapter.gui.wizard"> for more details on this window), by selecting the
  <code>File -> Generate -> New CDD...</code> menu option, or using the shortcut "Shift-Control-N".  This file creation
  "wizard" allows the user to create a new CDD file that can be opened/merged into the GUI for coverage analysis.  The
  methods that the CDD creation GUI allows for creating a new CDD file are quite flexible and are completely compatible
  with the command-line commands.
  </para>
  <para>
  The following subsections describe the various windows used to create a GUI.  Note that the CDD creation wizard
  uses several "pages" to describe the various options to set for creating a new CDD file, using "Back" and "Next" 
  buttons on each page for navigation.  Clicking on the "Back" button will not cause previously filled in pages to be
  reverted to their default values but rather will remain populated with the user's data. Similarly, if a page has been
  filled in with data and the "Back" button is clicked and then the "Next" button is clicked, the page contents are
  retained.  The only way to clear out fields is to click the "Cancel" button at the bottom of each page and startup
  the CDD creation wizard again.
  </para>
  <para>
  Clicking the "Cancel" button at any time will cause the CDD creation wizard to immediately exit.  Clicking on the
  "Help" button at any time will bring up the user documentation for the current page (context sensitive help).
  </para>
  
  <sect1 id="section.gui.new.select" xreflabel="Navigating the New CDD Creation Option Selection Page">
    <title>Navigating the New CDD Creation Option Selection Window</title>
    <para>
    Figure <xref linkend="figure.gui.new.select"> shows the look of this page of the CDD creation wizard.
    </para>
    <para>
      <figure id="figure.gui.new.select" xreflabel="CDD Creation Option Selection Page">
        <title>CDD Creation Option Selection Page</title>
        <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="img/new_cdd_selection.gif" format="GIF"></imageobject></mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </para>
    <para>
    The first page of the CDD creation window allows the user to select whether all options should be interactiely
    selected within the GUI or if a file should be read in which contains command-line options to the score command
    to use.  If the latter is chosen, the contents of that file are read in and are populated in the GUI, but the
    CDD creation wizard will continue in the same fashion as the first option, allowing the user to change, remove or
    add to the options found in that file.
    </para>
    <para>
    If the "Create CDD by interactively selecting options" entry is currently selected and the user wishes to not use
    a command-line file to populate the rest of the CDD creation pages, simply click on the "Next" button at the
    bottom of the page to continue.  If the "Create CDD by using option file" entry is currently selected, the user
    must either type a valid filename or select one by clicking the "Browse..." button to the right of the file entry
    area and select a valid file.  Once a valid filename is selected, the "Next" button will be enabled and the user
    may then click it to continue to the next page.  Note that any filename can be selected (whether it's a valid
    command file or not).  Only valid score command options found in that file are used to populate the wizard entries.
    No error message will be displayed if the file does not contain this information.
    </para>
  </sect1>
</chapter>