<chapter id="chapter.rank" xreflabel="The rank Command">
  <title>The rank Command</title>
  <para>
  TBD
  </para>
  
  <sect1 id="section.rank.options" xreflabel="Rank Options">
    <title>Options</title>
    <para>
      <table>
        <title>Options to rank Command</title>
        <tgroup cols='2'>
          <thead>
            <row>
              <entry>
              Option
              </entry>
              <entry>
              Description
              </entry>
            </row>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
              -depth <emphasis>number</emphasis>
              </entry>
              <entry>
              Specifies the minimum number of CDD files to hit each coverage point. The value of 
              <emphasis>number</emphasis> should be a value of 1 or more.  Default is 1.
              </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>
              -f <emphasis>filename</emphasis>
              </entry>
              <entry>
              Name of file containing additional arguments to parse.
              </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>
              -h
              </entry>
              <entry>
              Displays help information for the rank command.
              </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>
              -names-only
              </entry>
              <entry>
              If specified, outputs only the needed CDD filenames that need to be run in the order they need to be run. 
              If this option is not set, a report-style output is provided with additional information.
              </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>
              -o <emphasis>filename</emphasis>
              </entry>
              <entry>
              Name of file to output ranking information to.  Default is stdout.
              </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>
              -weight-assert <emphasis>number</emphasis>
              </entry>
              <entry>
              Specifies a relative weighting for assertion coverage used to rank non-unique coverage points.
              </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>
              -weight-comb <emphasis>number</emphasis>
              </entry>
              <entry>
              Specifies a relative weighting for combinational logic coverage used to rank non-unique coverage points.
              </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>
              -weight-fsm <emphasis>number</emphasis>
              </entry>
              <entry>
              Specifies a relative weighting for FSM state/state transition coverage used to rank non-unique coverage 
              points.
              </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>
              -weight-line <emphasis>number</emphasis>
              </entry>
              <entry>
              Specifies a relative weighting for line coverage used to rank non-unique coverage points.
              </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>
              -weight-memory <emphasis>number</emphasis>
              </entry>
              <entry>
              Specifies a relative weighting for memory coverage used to rank non-unique coverage points.
              </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>
              -weight-toggle <emphasis>number</emphasis>
              </entry>
              <entry>
              Specifies a relative weighting for toggle coverage used to rank non-unique coverage points.
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
    </para>
  </sect1>
</chapter>
